<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook"
         xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
         xsi:schemaLocation="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/5.0b3/xsd/docbook.xsd">

    <title>Key Types</title>

    <para>
        There are two key types to understand when working with RxJava, and a subset of auxiliary types that will help
        you to learn Rx more effectively. The
        <tag>Observer&lt;T&gt;</tag>
        and
        <tag>Observable&lt;T&gt;</tag>
        form the fundamental building blocks for Rx, while implementations of
        <tag>Subject&lt;TSource, TResult&gt;</tag>
        reduce the learning curve for developers new to RxJava.
    </para>

    <sect1>
        <title>Observable&lt;T&gt;</title>

        <para>
            In RxJava an object that implements the <tag>Observer</tag> interface subscribes to an object of the
            Observable class. Then that subscriber reacts to whatever item or sequence of items the Observable
            object emits. This pattern facilitates concurrent operations because it does not need to block while
            waiting for the Observable to emit objects, but instead it creates a sentry in the form of a
            subscriber that stands ready to react appropriately at whatever future time the Observable does so.
        </para>

        <para>
            This section explains what the reactive pattern is and what <tag>Observable</tag>s and <tag>Observer</tag>s
            are (and how observers subscribe to Observables). Next chapters show how you use the variety of
            Observable operators to link Observables together and change their behaviors.
        </para>

        <mediaobject>
            <caption>Observable Marble</caption>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="img/observable.png" format="PNG" width="50%" depth="50%" align="center"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>

        <sect2>
            <title>Background</title>
        </sect2>

        <sect2>
            <title>Establishing Subscribers</title>
        </sect2>

        <sect2>
            <title>“Hot” and “Cold” Observables</title>
        </sect2>

    </sect1>

    <sect1>
        <title>Subscriber&lt;T&gt;</title>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
        <title>Subject&lt;T&gt;</title>
    </sect1>

    <!--
    <sect1>
        <title>Creating an Observable from an Existing Data Structure</title>
    </sect1>


    <sect1>
        <title>Creating an Observable via the
            <tag>create()</tag>
            method
        </title>

        <sect2>
            <title>Synchronous Observable Example</title>
        </sect2>

        <sect2>
            <title>Asynchronous Observable Example</title>
        </sect2>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
        <title>Transforming Observables with Operators</title>
    </sect1>

    <sect1>
        <title>Error Handling</title>
    </sect1>
    -->

</chapter>